# **Travis Tincher**

# **Software Engineer**

**Email:** tincher.travis@gmail.com

Phone: (903) 574-1520

LinkedIn: linkedin.com/in/travis-tincher

GitHub: github.com/trtincher

#### **SUMMARY**

I am a software engineer driven by collaboration and curiosity. My focus is on end-to-end full stack feature work. I design, build, and ship well-tested, maintainable features prioritizing the end user experience. As a team member or leader I aim to empower teammates. Fundamentally, every contribution I make is driven by creative innovation.

#### **Skills**

- Languages:
   Typescript / Javascript
   / Ruby / Java
- Frameworks: Node.js / Ruby on Rails / Spring / React / React Native / NestJS
  - DevOps: CI / CD/ Git / CMS / AWS / GCP / Firebase / Heroku
- Backend: Rest API / GraphQL / Postgres / SQL / Express

#### **EXPERIENCE**

**DeepSeas** Remote

Software Engineer - Contractor

FEBRUARY 2023 - PRESENT

- Contribute to both **Ruby on Rails** and **NestJS** projects at Deep Seas Development, an **AWS**-focused engineering firm, ensuring performant, scalable, and cost-effective cloud applications.
- Lead a collaborative upgrade of a legacy **Rails** application from **Ruby** 2/**Rails** 5 to **Ruby** 3/**Rails** 7, enhancing security, maintainability, and alignment with modern industry standards.
- Develop and maintain scalable backend services in **NestJS** using **TypeScript** and **PostgreSQL**, ensuring high-quality code and efficient data management across applications.

**Alix** Remote

## Software Engineer - Full-time

MAY 2023 - DECEMBER 2024

- Devised an innovative approach to automate sorting of large sets of PDF documents using a combination of **AWS** S3, **AWS** Textract, and OpenAI combined with internal business logic exposing the tool through a **NodeJS / GraphQL API** interface. This reduced the manual processing time by 80%, saving the company an average of 15 hours per client.
- Streamlined front-end development and enforced coding standards by creating a reusable custom React
  component library, automating form UI generation from GraphQL schemas, and integrating Apollo
  Codegen for Typescript automation, improving code maintainability and reducing new feature
  development effort by at least 25%.
- Collaborated closely with UI/UX Designers to execute streamlined customer facing features in a **React** client with an emphasis on cross-browser compliant HTML & CSS.

**TouchTo** Remote

## Software Engineer - Contractor

FEBRUARY 2023 - MAY 2023

 Developed educational web applications for Texas elementary schools using React Native, TypeScript, and GraphQL, including interactive games to teach children about the environment and ecology. Worked closely with accessibility experts for a fully compliant UX experience.

JMJ Financial Remote

### Lead Backend Software Engineer - Full-time

JANUARY 2021 - JANUARY 2023

- Mortgage Disclosures B2B2C: Architected and implemented a full-stack Ruby on Rails/TypeScript feature
  using REST API integrations with Encompass and HelloSign APIs, translating data to fit various schemas,
  and creating webhooks for an event-driven document approval process. This feature significantly improved
  the legacy solution with an enhanced customer interface and reduced manual overhead by an estimated
  60%.
- Designed **REST APIs** and database architecture in **PostgreSQL** to support workflows for 3 different customer bases and created generative scripts extending **Ruby on Rails** scaffolding.
- Managed deliverables for multiple projects by tracking progress, delegating work to external contractors, resolving blockers, and collaborating with team members to ensure timely delivery.

### Junior Frontend Software Engineer - Full-time

FEBRUARY 2020 - JANUARY 2021

- Created admin forms **UI** and views with **Ruby on Rails** for visualization and maintenance of user data for the purpose of processing home loans.
- Built interactive customer forms in **React** to create a digital version of the Uniform Residential Loan Application (Form 1003).

Ctrl Alt Elite Remote

## Frontend Software Engineer - Freelance

SEPTEMBER 2020 - FEBRUARY 2021

• Developed a responsive **React** web application for a mobile bike mechanic, which included key features such as a Calendly for scheduling, a Google Maps for location mapping.

#### **EDUCATION**

# General Assembly Remote

Software Engineering and Development, August 2020

Earned 1st place in General Assembly's Alumni Social Impact Hackathon for myBallot WA **React.js** application.

 Designed and created 2 front end applications and 1 full stack application using React.js and Ruby on Rails.

# Emory University Atlanta, GA

Master of Theological Studies, May 2015

Texas A&M College Station, TX

Bachelor of Arts in Philosophy, August 2012